Guide to the Archives of Irish America Pamphlet Collection AIA.047
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America Pamphlet Collection
1843-1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America
AIA.047
2.5 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons and 1 manuscript box
The materials in this collection were collected, purchased, and assembled by the staff of the Archives of Irish America and various donors in an attempt to document the variety of pamphlets produced by and for the Irish American community. The collection includes pamphlets, leaflets, and booklets concerning socialism, labor relations, Irish immigration, Irish republicanism, England's relationship with Ireland, and conflict in Northern Ireland, with specific emphasis on deportation cases, the 1981 hunger strikes, and British military practices. Major writers represented include Éamon de Valera, James Connolly, Sean O'Casey, Gerald O'Reilly, Bobby Sands, and Francis Sheehy-Skeffington.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
George Harrison Papers AIA 009
Archives of Irish America Vertical Files Collection AIA 013
Irish Republicanism Collection AIA 022
Patrick Daughton Papers AIA 055
Ernie O'Malley Papers AIA 060
Arrangement
Pamphlets are arranged into two series: Series I. General Collection, 1843-1992; Series II. Ernie O'Malley Pamphlet Collection, 1903-1924. Pamphlets are organized alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Custodial History
Received from and purchased by Archives of Irish America staff and numerous donors in multiple installments, beginning in 1996. Some of the pamphlets were removed from manuscripts collections, most notably from the Cormac K.H. O'Malley Papers and Ernie O'Malley Papers, and transferred to this collection to facilitate access. The accession number associated with materials separated from the Cormac K.H. O'Malley Papers is 2000.025 and the accession number associated with the materials separated from the Ernie O'Malley Papers is 2010.092. The accession number for the 2019 accretion is 2019.105.
Historical Note
The materials in this collection were collected, purchased, and assembled by the staff of the Archives of Irish America and various donors in an attempt to document the variety of pamphlets produced by and for the Irish American community.
Scope and Contents
The Archives of Irish America Pamphlet Collection is an intentionally assembled collection of various pamphlets, leaflets, and booklets published by and for the Irish American community. The pamphlets date from as early as 1843 and provide social and political commentary on activities in Ireland and America. Topics include socialism, labor relations, Irish immigration, Irish republicanism, England's relationship with Ireland, and conflict in Northern Ireland, with specific emphasis on deportation cases, the 1981 hunger strikes, and British military practices. Major writers represented include Éamon de Valera, James Connolly, Sean O'Casey, Gerald O'Reilly, Bobby Sands, and Francis Sheehy-Skeffington. Of note is a copy of An Smaointeori, the magazine for the Gaelic League of the State of New York, signed by Irish republican and Sinn Féin politician Liam Mellows.
Poems.; Bloody Sunday, Derry, Northern Ireland, 1972.; Northern Ireland -- History -- 1969-1994.; Socialism |z Ireland.; Ireland -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Emigration and immigration law -- United States.; Hunger strikes -- Northern Ireland.; Peace movements |z Northern Ireland.; Violence -- Northern Ireland.; Ireland -- History -- 20th century.; Human rights |z Ireland.; Socialism.; Pamphlets.; Prisoners' writings, Irish.; McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin, 1947-; Cork Workers' Club; Connolly, James, 1868-1916; Socialist Labor Party; Irish Republican Army; Goulding, Cathal, 1922-1998; Larkin, James, 1876-1947; O'Reilly, Gerald, 1903-1990; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964; De Valera, Eamon, 1882-1975; AE, 1867-1935; Irish Northern Aid Committee; Sands, Bobby, d. 1981; Dail Eireann; Doherty, Joseph Patrick, 1955-; Irish Transport and General Workers' Union; Sheehy-Skeffington, Francis, 1878-1916; Gralton, Jimmy, 1886-1945; Russell, George William, 1867-1935
- General Collection, 1843-1992; 238855
  - 1913: Jim Larkin and the Dublin Lock-out. Workers' Union of Ireland, Dublin., May 1964; 290722 (Box 1)
  - 1934 Republican Congress by George Gilmore. Inscribed "Gerald O'Reilly with best wishes George Gilmore", 300124 (Box 1)
  - The AFL-CIO and Justice in Northern Ireland. Irish Northern Aid Committee. San Francisco, 1971; 344235 (Box 1)
  - American Citizens Imprisoned in Ireland: Message from the President of the United States. James K. Polk, House of Representatives. Washington, D.C., Dec 27, 1948; 258924 (Box 1)
  - The American Irish. American Irish Awareness Committee, Incorporated. Stony Point, NY., 1987, 1990; 236978 (Box 1)
  - The American Way to Ireland. (Tourist Map) Irish Emigrant Society. New York., undated; 236984 (Box 1)
  - An Alleged First Census of the American People. Michael J. O'Brien, LLD. American Irish Historical Society. New York., 1930; 251203 (Box 1)
  - An Address From the Army Council of the Irish Republican Army to the Men and Women of the Orange Order.", 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - An Appreciation of Padric H. Pearse, First President of the Irish Republic. William G. O'Farrell, Chas. F. Connolly, Union Label Printer. New York., undated; 251200 (Box 1)
  - The Axe to the Root and Old Wine in New Bottles. James Connolly. Repsol Pamphlet No. 14. Dublin., undated; 336510 (Box 1)
  - The Banks. Introduction by Eamonn Smullen. Studies in Political Economy. Research Section, Department of Economic Affairs. Repsol Publications/Sinn Fein The Workers' Party. Dublin., 1976; 336509 (Box 1)
  - Being Young in West Belfast. The Workers Party Republican Clubs. Belfast., 1976; 336508 (Box 1)
  - Belfast Politics. United Irish Reprints No. 4, Athol Books, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bernadette Devlin McAliskey on the Irish Freedom Struggle. Pathfinder Press. New York., 1982; 242163 (Box 1)
  - The Best of Times: Reminiscences. John Grimes, 1989; 351639 (Box 1)
  - Birth and Growth of the Transport Workers Union: The Straight Story of How a Dedicated Few Realized Their Dreams and Built a Powerful Union. Gerald O'Reilly., undated; 242205 (Box 1)
  - Britain's War Machine in Ireland. Maurice Burke, SMA. Irish American Defense Fund. New York, circa 1985; 281339 (Box 1)
  - Britain's War Machine in Ireland. Maurice Burke, SMA. Oisin Publications. New York, 1987; 340273 (Box 1)
  - British Army Terror Tactics, West Belfast, September-October 1976. Father Brian Brady, Father Denis Faul, and Father Raymond Murray. Dungannon, Tyrone, circa 1977; 453033 (Box 1)
  - British Government Violations of Human Rights in N. Ireland: A Study of an Attempted Military Solution to a Polical Problem. Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association. Belfast, undated; 336507 (Box 1)
  - British Imperialism in Ireland. Being a Digest of a Lecture Delivered in U.S.A. in 1926. Hanna Sheehy Skeffington. Clo Na Saoirse. Dublin, 336506 (Box 1)
  - British Troops Must Go. United Irishman, Dublin, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Burntollet. Bowes Egan and Vincent McCormack. LRS Publishers. London, 1969; 453034 (Box 1, Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Case Against the Common Market: Why Ireland Should Not Join. Assessment 2. Republican Publications. Dublin, 1967; 336505 (Box 1)
  - The Case for Irish-American Unity. Terence O'Donnell. Catholicism and the Crisis. Justice Frank Murphy. American Council on Public Affairs. Washington, D.C., undated; 242164 (Box 1)
  - Challenge of Socialism. Professor Benjamin Farrington. Review. Dublin, circa 1947; 242159 (Box 1)
  - Charter, Constitution, By-Laws, Officers, Committees, Roll of Members. Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick in the City of New York, 1922; 351638 (Box 1)
  - The Cause of Ireland and Adopted Citizens. The Record of J.T. Hoffman. His Views on Fenianism ... His Message to the Common Council Relative to the Rights of Adopted Citizens, dated Nov. 30, 1867. [New York], 344233 (Box 1)
  - The Connolly DeLeon Controversy. On Wages, Marriage and the Church. Cork Worker's Club. Belfast, 1904; 291961 (Box 1)
  - The Connolly-Walker Controversy. On Socialist Unity in Ireland. Cork Workers Club. Historical Reprints No. 9. Cork, Nov 1974; 336504 (Box 1)
  - The Connolly-Walker Controversy. On Socialist Unity in Ireland. Cork Worker's Club. Belfast, 1911; 291958 (Box 1)
  - Convict No. 50945: Jim Larkin Irish Labour Leader. Cork Worker's Club. Belfast, 1923, reprint 1975; 291959 (Box 1)
  - The Crunch Has Come. Frankie O'Brien. Boulevard Offset Co. Baltimore, Maryland, Mar 1981; 453035 (Box 1)
  - Culture and Revolution in Ireland. Eoin O' Murchu. Repsol Pamphlet. Republican Education Department. Dublin, 1971; 242165 (Box 1, Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Daniel O'Connell The Irish Patriot. Wendell Phillips. Lee and Shepherd Publishers. Boston, 1884; 242193 (Box 1)
  - De-Americanizing Young America: Poisoning the Sources of our National History and Traditions by Edward F. McSweeney. Boston, Apr 1920; 344709 (Box 1)
  - A Decade of Deceit: A Detailed Look at the New York Times and The War in Ireland. Irish Northern Aid. New York, 1981; 236974 (Box 1)
  - Direct Rule: Civil Rights Not Civil War." Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Driftnetting of Salmon in Ireland: Allegations and Truth. National Fishermen's Defence Association, 1974; 336503 (Box 1)
  - The Economics of Ireland and the Policy of the British Government. George W. Russell ("AE"). Freeman Pamphlets. R.W. Huebsch, Inc. New York., 1920; 291246 (Box 1)
  - The EEC: An Alternative. Repsol Pamphlet No. 7, Dublin, 1971; 336502 (Box 1)
  - The EEC: Ireland and the Making of a Superpower. Anthony Coughlan. Irish Sovereignty Movement. Dublin, May 1979; 336501 (Box 1)
  - Eire: The New Constitution, The Citizen's Manual, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Eire Nua. Ruairi O'Bradaigh and Sean Mac Stiofain. Elo Press Ltd. Dublin, Jun 28, 1972; 453036 (Box 1)
  - Eire Nua: The Social and Economic Programme of Sinn Fein. Dublin, 1971; 236988 (Box 1)
  - Erin: Her Sisters, Her Nurse and Her Doctors. Rev. Robert Shapland Carew Blacker. William Ridgway, London, 1881; 344234 (Box 1)
  - Erin's Hope: The End and the Means and The New Evangel. James Connolly. New Books Publications. Dublin, 1968; 236985 (Box 1)
  - The Empire Strikes Back: The Taking of Joe Doherty. James T. Kelly, Fordham Law Review, Vol. LXI, No. 2. New York, Nov 1992; 238853 (Box 1)
  - England, Germany, and the Irish Question by an English Catholic. Hodder and Stoughton. New York (2 copies), 1917; 238854 (Box 1)
  - English Atrocities in Ireland; a Compilation of Facts from Court and Press Records. Katherine Hughes. Friends of Irish Freedom, Inc. New York, 1920; 344236 (Box 1)
  - Fellowship. Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fireside Songs, nos. 6-8. Walton's Musical Instrument Galleries. Dublin, undated; 453037 (Box 1)
  - Focus: The Irish Question. M. Gearoid Baireid and Liam O' Murchadha. Eire Nua, Inc. Hillside, New Jersey, Mar 1974; 453038 (Box 1)
  - For or Against the Ranchers?: Irish Working Farmers in the Economic War Peadar O'Donnell. Mayo News, Westport, 1911; 336500 (Box 1)
  - The Foundation of the Republic of Ireland in the Vote of the People", circa 1919 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Free and Gaelic: Pearse's Idea of a National Culture by Sean Patrick Walsh. Coiste Chomoradh an Phiarsaigh. Dublin (In English and Irish), Jun 1979; 336499 (Box 1)
  - Freedom Stuggle by the Provisional I.R.A. Irish Northern Aid. New York, 1974; 236986 (Box 1)
  - Freedom's Road for Irish Works. "Ronald." Cork Worker's Club. Belfast, 1917, reprinted 1975; 291960 (Box 1)
  - The Gralton Affair: The Story of the Deportation of Jim Gralton a Leitrim Socialist in 1933. Pat Feeley. Coolock Free Press. Dublin, 1986; 236990 (Box 1)
  - The Great Irish Oil and Gas Robbery: A Case Study of Monopoly Capital. Research Section. Department of Economic Affairs, Repsol Publications/Sinn Fein The Workers' Party. Dublin (see Poster in AIA 055), 1977; 336498 (Box 1)
  - A Handbook of Republican Relations. National Book Service. Dublin, undated; 336497 (Box 1)
  - H Block: The British Government's Treatment of Irish Political Prisoners. By H-Block Information Centre. Belfast, 1978; 453039 (Box 1)
  - H-Block and its Background. Denis Faul and Raymond Murray. Published in: Doctrine and Life. Dublin, 1980; 236992 (Box 1)
  - The H Blocks: An Indictment of British Prison Policy in the North of Ireland. Information on Ireland. London, 1981; 294497 (Box 1)
  - Health Care: The Case for Socialist Medical Care. Dr. John McManus. Repsol/Sinn Fein-The Workers' Party Publication. Dublin, 1977; 336496 (Box 1)
  - Historical Basis of Socialism in Ireland. Thomas Brady. Socialist Labor Party. New York, 1921; 242197 (Box 1)
  - The Historical Basis of Socialism in Ireland. Thomas Brady. Cork Workers Club Historical Reprints No. 8. Cork, Nov 1974; 336495 (Box 1)
  - History of Ireland (unfinished). Frederick Engels. Irish Worker's Group. London, 1965, reprinted 1966; 236977 (Box 2)
  - The Hooded Men: British Torture in Ireland, August-October 1971. Father Denis Faul and Father Raymond Murray. Dungannon, Tyrone, 1974; 453040 (Box 1)
  - The Hunger Strike and the Final Struggle. Seamus Proinsias Metress. Center for Irish American Studies. Toledo, OH (2 copies), 1983; 251202 (Box 1)
  - I gCuis na hEireann" / In the Cause of Ireland. Speech by Cathal Goulding, Bodenstown. Irish Republican Clubs, U.S.A and Canada., Jun 1975; 336494 (Box 1)
  - Immigrating USA: A Guide for Irish Immigrants. New York: Project Irish Outreach, Catholic Charities, Archdiocese of New York, circa 1987; 236982 (Box 1)
  - In Memorium Sean Sabat and Feargal O' hAnnluain, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - India and Ireland. Eamon DeValera. Friends of Freedom for India. New York, 1920; 242198 (Box 1)
  - The Indictment. Hon. Daniel F. Cohalan. Friends of Irish Freedom. New York, Jul 1919; 344237 (Box 1)
  - "Inside the IRA: Interviews with Cathal Goulding, Chief of Staff, IRA". Recon, Vol. III, No. 1, Jan 1975; 336492 (Box 1)
  - International Obligations and the Irish Question. Sean O'Cionnaith. Reposl Pamphlet No. 18. Dublin, undated; 336491 (Box 1)
  - Ireland and British Misrule: Lloyd George's Insincerity. Friends of Irish Freedom National Bureau of Information. Washington, D.C., 1920; 251199 (Box 1)
  - Ireland and the Irish in the U.S.A. James Larkin. Transport Workers Union of America, C.I.O. New York. (2 copies), 1947; 236989 (Box 1)
  - Ireland and the Socialist Countries Text of speech delivered by Sean Garland, General Secretary The Workers' Party to a meeting of Party members in Dublin, Jan 1986; 336490 (Box 1)
  - Ireland and the War. Speeches delivered by John E. Redmon, M.P. (Leader of the Irish Party), at Dublin and Kilkenny, on September 25th and October 18th, 1914. Reprinted from Freeman's Journal., 336489 (Box 1)
  - Ireland in Rebellion: Including Interviews with Cathal Goudling, Chief of Staff, Irish Republican Army, and Tomas Mac Giolla. President, Sinn Fein. Gerry Foley. Pathfinder Press. New York, 1971; 236983 (Box 1)
  - Ireland: The Socialist Answer. Worker's Ireland Pamphlet. London, circa 1990; 242160 (Box 1)
  - Ireland Upon the Dissecting Table: James Connolly on Ulster and Partition. Cork Workers Club Historical Reprints No. 11. Cork, May 1975; 336488 (Box 1)
  - Ireland's Fight for Freedom and the Irish in the U.S.A. Sean Murray. Workers Library Publishers. New York. (2 copies), Jun 1934; 239306 (Box 1)
  - Ireland's Fight for Freedom and the Irish in the U.S.A. Sean Murray. Workers Library Publishers. New York, 1934; 251210 (Box 1)
  - Ireland's Path to Freedom: Manifest of the Communist Party of Ireland. Sean Murray. Workers Library Publishers. New York, 1934; 242196 (Box 1)
  - Ireland's Right to Sovereignty, Independence, and Unity is Inalienable and Indefeasible. Sean MacBride, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Ireland's Way Forward: Report of the Irish Communist Conference. W. H. M'Cullough. Belfast, Oct 1942; 251170 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Answer, 1984; 453041 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Case for Communism. Sean Murray. Workers Library Publishers. New York (4 copies), 1934; 236987 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Question. John Leslie. Cork Workers Club Historical Reprints No. 7. Cork, Oct 1974; 336486 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Question. V.I. Lenin. Repsol Pulications. Dublin, undated; 336487 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Question: Federation or Succession. F. S. Oliver. Civil Service Printing Co. New York, undated; 251196 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Republican Congress. George Gilmore. United Irish Republican Committee of the U.S. New York, 1935; 242195 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Republican Congress by George Gilmore. Cork Workers Club Historical Reprints No. 4. Cork., Aug 1974; 336484 (Box 1)
  - The Irish Republican Digest, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Irish Revolt: 1916 and After. Sean Murry. Community Party of Great Britain. London, undated; 336483 (Box 1)
  - Irish Women Speak. Women for Irish Freedom. New York, 1973; 336482 (Box 1)
  - Irish Workers' Road to Freedom: Manifest of the Irish Workers' League. Executive Committee of the Irish Worker's League. Dublin, June 1949; 291939 (Box 1)
  - I Speak to Catholics: A Priest raises his Voice for Spain. Father Michael O'Flanagan. Irish American Education League, San Francisco, 1938; 336493 (Box 1)
  - Is Southern Ireland a Neo-Colony? Kieran Allen. Bookmarks. Dublin, 1990; 251171 (Box 1)
  - James Connolly and Irish Freedom: A Marxist Analysis. G. Schuller. Cork Workers Club Historical Reprints No. 1. Cork, 1974; 336481 (Box 1)
  - James Connolly and Irish Freedom: A Marxist Analysis. G. Schuller. Cork Worker's Club. Cork, Ireland (originally published in 1926), 1976; 291944 (Box 1)
  - The James Connolly Songbook. Cork Workers Club, Cork, Oct 1972; 336480 (Box 1)
  - "Jim" Connolly and Irish Freedom. G. Schuller. Daily Worker Publishing Company. Little Red Library No. 11. Chicago, circa 1926; 251211 (Box 1)
  - John Joe McGirl, The Gentle Soldier: Memorial. Friends of County Leitrim. Reprinted, United States, 1991; 236975 (Box 1)
  - Justice Denied: A Challenge to Lord Widgery's Report on 'Bloody Sunday'. Samuel Dash. Defense and Education Fund of the International League for the Rights of Man, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Kilmainham: The Bastille of Ireland. Kilmainham Jail Restoration Society, 1970; 336479 (Box 1)
  - Labor, Nationality and Religion. James Connolly. James Connolly Socialist Club. New York, 1918; 242199 (Box 1)
  - The Labour Party and Ireland: Northern Options. Irish Workers Organisation (Clann na hEireann); Birmingham, London, undated; 336974 (Box 1)
  - Labour and the Republican Movement. George Gilmore. Repsol Pamphlet. Dublin, undated; 336478 (Box 1)
  - Labour Nationality and Religion. James Connolly. Irish Transport and General Workers' Union. Dublin, 1935; 336477 (Box 1)
  - The Leggings and The Bandoliers: A Poem. Charlie Gimore. Repsol Publications. Dublin, 1976; 336476 (Box 1)
  - Lenin on Ireland. New Books Publications. Dublin, 1974; 336475 (Box 1)
  - Let the Nation Stand. Padraig Yeates. Repsol Pamphlet Number 15. Republican Education Department. Dublin, 1974; 336474 (Box 1)
  - Liberty or Slavery? Daniel O'Connell on American Slavery. Reply to O'Connell by Hon. S.P. Chase. Committee of the Friends of Liberty, Ireland, and Repeal. Cicinnatti, OH, 1843; 242194 (Box 1)
  - Lost Liberties: The Offences Against the State Act. Elo Press. Dublin, Mar 1972; 453042 (Box 1)
  - Manifesto of Leaders of the Intellectual Life of Great Britain on Ireland and Report of the British Labor Commission to Ireland. The World Tomorrow. New York, 1920; 251197 (Box 1)
  - Manifesto of the Socialist Party of Ireland with Declaration of Principles, 1949; 336473 (Box 1)
  - Marx and the Irish Question. Sean Cronin. Repsol Publications. Dublin, 1977; 336472 (Box 2)
  - Marx, Engels and Lenin on Ireland. Ralph Fox. International Publishers. New York, 1940; 337410 (Box 2)
  - Marx, Engels and Lenin on the Irish Revolution. Ralph Fox. Cork Workers Club Historical Reprints No. 3. Cork, Aug 1974; 336471 (Box 2)
  - Massacre at Derry. Civil Rights Association. New York, undated; 236981 (Box 2, Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Murder of James Crossan. United Irishman, Dublin., circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The New Evangel. James Connolly. Socialist Party of Ireland. Dublin; The Rights of Ireland and The Faith of Felon. James Fintan Lawlor. 1848. Socialist Party of Ireland. Dublin. Reprinted from the Irish Felon. (Poor condition - use photocopies), circa 1948; 336470 (Box 2)
  - New Ireland Forum: Report. The Stationery Office. Dublin, 1984; 236979 (Box 2)
  - News Letter of the Friends of the Irish Freedmon National Bureau of Information. Terrence McSwiney and Patrick Henry. Vol II, Nos. 7, 10. Washington, D.C., Sep 4, 1920; 251206 (Box 2)
  - Northern Ireland: Facts at your Fingertips. Northern Ireland Information Service, Belfast, Jun 1975; 336973 (Box 2)
  - Northern Ireland: Finance and the Economy. Northern Ireland Office, Her Majesty's Stationery Office, London, 1974; 337411 (Box 2)
  - Northern Ireland: From Civil Rights to Armed Struggle. Russell Stetler. New England Free Press, 1970; 336975 (Box 2)
  - Northern Ireland. Reference Division. Central Office of Information, London, May 1975; 336972 (Box 2)
  - Northern Ireland -- The Mailed Fist: A Record of Army and Police Brutality from Aug 9-Nov 9, 1971, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - O'Connor's Blackmail Mission Exposed. Sinn Fein League of America., 1909; 242201 (Box 2)
  - Olaig na hEireann. Republican Information Bureau, Dublin, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - O'Neills Pocket Guide to Irish New York. O'Neill's Five Points Press. New York (2 copies), 1983; 236993 (Box 2)
  - Owen Wister: Advocate of Racial Hatred. An Unpatriotic American Who Seeks to Destroy American Traditions. Danield T. O'Connell. Friends of Irish Freedom National Bureau of Information. Washington, D.C., May 1920; 251195 (Box 2)
  - Pages from History on Irish-Soviet Relations. Michael O'Riordan, General Secretary, Communist Party of Ireland. New Book Publications. Dublin, 1977; 336469 (Box 2)
  - The Partition of Ireland: How Britain is Responsible. Henry Harrison. Robert Hale Limited, London, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Partition of Ireland: How and Why it was Accomplished. David O'Neill. M.H. Gill and Son, Ltd. Dublin, 1947; 336468 (Box 2)
  - Patrick Ford of the Irish World. Rev. John Talbot Smith, undated; 242204 (Box 2)
  - The Planting of the Seed: An Account of the Founding of the Irish Transport and General Worker's Union and the Role it Played in the Period Up to the Rising in 1916. Cathal O'Shannon. National Executive Council of the Irish Transport and General Worker's Union. Dublin, 1966; 236980 (Box 2)
  - Poems of the Irish Republic. Peter Golden., undated; 251198 (Box 2)
  - Police Persecution of Patriot Family. United Irish Republicans. Bronx, NY, circa 1940; 292059 (Box 2)
  - Prelude to Freedom 1916-1966 50th Anniversary Review. Irish Art Publications, Ltd., Dublin, 336467 (Box 2)
  - Prison Poems. Bobby Sands. Dublin: Sinn Fein Publicity Department, 1981; 242162 (Box 2)
  - Problems of the Irish Revolution: Can the IRA Meet the Challenge? Gerry Foley. Pathfinder Press. New York, 1972; 236991 (Box 2)
  - The Provisionals: Agents or Dupes of Imperialism. An Analysis. Irish Republican Clubs of USA-Canada. Woodside, NY, 1975; 242166 (Box 2)
  - The Public Sector and the Profit Makers: The Case for State Workers. Repsol Pamphlet No. 19. Research Section Department of Economic Affairs, Sinn Fein, Dublin, 1975; 336466 (Box 2)